Everyone decided to show their incomplete, entire asses.
Oh, God.
And, like, in irrevocable ways.
What a Joke with Papa and Fortune.
On Netflix's Joke Radio.
Sirius XM Channel 93.
Welcome, everybody, to What a Joke with Papa and Fortune.
I'm Tom Papa.
I'm Fortune Feimster.
And we're very excited because our new friend, Amanda Seals, is here.
Hi, guys.
Hey, nice to see you.
You too.
She has a new book that just came out called Small Doses.
You can get it everywhere that books are sold.
I have it in my hands right now.
It's cool.
That's also the name of your podcast.
Yes.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Very nice.
I love that you say that it's where books are sold because someone literally asked me, like,
where can I get your book?
Right.
Where do you sell the book?
Yeah, right.
Exactly.
How was it writing it?
Everyone talks about how hard it is writing a book.
Right.
And so I thought, oh, my God, that's them.
Yeah.
It'll be different.
I was like, no, like, for me, it's going to be a piece of cake.
A walk in the park.
Yeah.
It was really hard.
It's a lot.
There's a lot in here.
This isn't.
It's a lot of brainiac-ness.
Yeah.
You didn't go light.
This is.
There's a lot here.
I mean, it's essentially like a resource.
But it's really just a humorous take on the facts of life for all intents and purposes
from my point of view.
And if you've seen my special, I'd be knowing, or you listen to my podcast, Small Doses, then
you know that I always shoot from the hip.
Yeah.
And I have a high quality quotient of common sense.
And, you know, and I really love pop culture.
So there's always like pop culture references thrown in there.
Yeah.
But I talk about like career, womanhood, race.
Ladies first.
Race realities.
Relationships.
What's Square Biz?
Square Biz is career.
Nice.
Baywatch.
Mm-hmm.
That's relationships.
Nice.
Bay spelled B-A-E.
B-A-E.
I was like, I love the show.
Right.
Pam.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
People are weird.
It looks like you went deep on a lot of stuff.
Yes.
Very cool.
I'm a deep broad.
I mean, I wanted to write something that would like last.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Goes on forever.
But you approach everything that way, it seems.
It seems like your act isn't.
Yeah, you're right.
Right?
You go, you're all in.
Yeah.
You're not messing around.
I'm not messing around.
You're hilarious, but you're also-
Thank you.
You know, saying something.
Gravitas.
Yeah.
Come on now.
This year, just in general, has been like a complete discombobulation of my prior understanding
of time management.
Right.
I did Bring the Funny for NBC.
Then I had my other show that I toured, Smart, Funny, and Black.
That was on a bus, so I thought, well, we're going to be on the bus.
I'll have time to do things.
Yeah, yeah.
Never at any point did I have time to do anything.
Right.
That was also a time when all of my agents decided to not be good agents.
Oh.
And my manager decided to not be a good manager, so I had to get rid of everybody.
My boyfriend decided to not be a good boyfriend.
It was like, everybody just decided, like, yeah, like, fuck you, Seagulls.
Oh, man.
That was a time when everybody needed to step it up.
Yeah, but when you do those kind of things, oh, she's on a bus.
She's, you know, out of sight, out of mind.
Everyone decided to show their complete entire asses.
Oh, God.
And, like, in irrevocable ways.
Oh, no.
Irreversible ways.
So it was just, like, a lot.
It was just, like, a lot all at once.
And then it was like, oh, shit, you have a book.
Yeah.
And the thing about this book thing is that I've never put out a book before.
I had to figure out so much of it on my own.
Yeah.
There just wasn't a lot of guidance.
And I felt very, like, alone.
And that just sucked.
So it's been, like, a year of literal, like, career dopeness.
Yeah.
But then, like, personal, I guess, like, my personal relationship to career.
It's a hard thing to figure out.
Especially when you've got that many, like, that really is what a good manager should
be helping you with, managing you through these things.
Oh, yeah.
No.
Yeah.
That didn't happen.
That manager's fired.
Yeah.
No.
You're fired.
Was that fun?
That's all you need.
Yeah.
I mean, I just think we're in this, like, time that is a very dark time.
Mm-hmm.
I think that it's easy to feel like it's not because we have a lot of great art that's
being created.
But when you look around, like, just, like, the consciousness of folks.
Yeah.
And I've even been noticing, like, the lasting effects of reality TV.
Uh-huh.
So, like, I've been hosting The Real for, like, two weeks as a guest host.
Mm-hmm.
And, like, we'll have conversations that sometimes get not even heated but passionate.
Yeah.
You know?
Like, they're just passionate discussions.
And it's not even, like, anybody's, like, necessarily on the wrong side of an argument.
It's more so just, like, okay, well, this is what I think.
What do you think?
Well, I don't know if I think that, you know?
Yeah.
And you'll have people who are, like, they're arguing with each other.
They don't like each other.
And I'm just like, what?
You're just having a conversation.
Yeah.
Like, we're literally having a heated, like, a passionate conversation.
Like, we're all smart.
Yeah.
We're talking about things.
And it's just like, oh, we've become so indoctrinated to, like, watching conflict on
television turn into a fight.
Oh, yeah.
That's, yeah.
Specifically with women of color.
Right.
And, like, I was on a live YouTube, like, live thing with Katy Perry.
Uh-huh.
And she had had this, like, dinner.
Mm-hmm.
Because she basically, like, voted for Hillary and her parents didn't.
And she didn't want to go home for Thanksgiving because she was like, I don't know what dinner
is going to be like.
Yeah.
Because we don't agree.
So she had this, like, live YouTube stream dinner with a bunch of different people that
have different points of view to kind of just, like, display to her fans, like, this
is what you do at a dinner where you have different points of view.
Yeah.
That's cool.
So it was, like, me, Margaret Cho.
Uh-huh.
Nice.
Um, this, this, uh, journalist, Derek Blacksburg, uh, cousin, DJ Skeeter, Van Jones.
Anna Navarro.
Mm-hmm.
Um, Sally Cohn and Caitlyn Jenner.
Oh, wow.
So, and at a point, at a certain point in the dinner, you know, there was a lot of kumbaya
talk happening.
Uh-huh.
You know, like, you know, like, Americans, like, all of us have a voice.
We should all be able to hear each other's voice.
Yeah.
You know, like, we all deserve a voice.
Like, we're all Americans.
And I was just quiet.
Playing with your peas.
Just playing with my peas.
Speaking of which, there was a last person there, and it was someone who had won a contest
to be there.
Oh, no.
They're just like, no one's talking to that person.
They're just like, hi, guys.
And that's literally what she was like.
She was like, this little, like, white girl was like, hi, guys.
Hi, guys.
I really love Katy Perry.
That's literally it.
And I know to this day, I'm like, I know she legit thought she was coming to play with
Katy's dog.
Yeah.
And ended up in, like, this, like, crossfire.
Oh, my God.
Really?
And, like, Van Jones was, like, our unspoken moderator.
Right.
So, he would, like, you know, throw the questions.
And then, in their kumbaya moment, Van was like, Amanda, like, what do you think?
And I was like, I mean, I think that we, I think that we're really overlooking the fact
that this guy, like, very strongly resembles the rhetoric of Hitler, like, in terms of his
methods and his cabinet.
And Caitlyn Jenner was just very upset about that.
She was very upset.
She said that it, she said, you know, this is something that's, it's just very, this conversation
is just not valid for me.
You know, I think it's very disrespectful to me as a citizen.
Oh, my God.
As an American.
Disrespectful to her?
Mm-hmm.
Personally.
And, uh, so she said all that, and I was just, like, because then I got quiet again.
Because, like, in those spaces, especially as a black woman, you're just, like, I'm not
gonna set myself up for you all to be, like, the angry black woman.
Like, I'm just not gonna do that.
It's when I'm talking pure, like, common sense.
I'm giving you facts.
Like, I'm not gonna do it.
So I got quiet again, and then she let, she did her spiel, and she was like, I just don't
want to talk.
I don't want to talk.
This conversation has become hostile.
Conversations have become hostile.
Oh, my God.
And Van finally was like, Amanda, what do you think?
And I was like, I mean, y'all, you know, now that you got her to talk, and he's like,
no, she talked, she talked.
I'm like, y'all had to literally, like, cajole and, like, really rub her back for her to talk.
I'm like, this is a dinner that's literally about this.
It's about the fact that we all come from different walks of life, and I'm not hostile.
I'm passionate.
And my life as a black woman in this country has been very different than yours, and she
scoffed about that.
And I had to, like, remind her.
I'm like, you know, like, America didn't show up for trans people until, like, 2 o'clock
today.
Right.
So, like, how is this, like, not computing for you?
Yeah.
You know?
But that clip went, like, viral to the roof.
Really?
And I went from, like, 44,000 followers on Instagram to, like, 100-something thousand
in, like, two days.
Holy cow.
Yeah.
It was, like, one of those, like, legit, like, you went viral.
Right.
Yeah.
And it was a very unique experience, too, because it's the only time I've gone viral a few times,
but it's the only time that I went viral and there was literally no negative pushback
whatsoever.
That was going to be my question.
Really?
None.
To this day.
Wow.
Zero.
That's remarkable.
Why do you think?
I genuinely don't truthfully know.
Yeah.
I mean, it was a miracle for all intents and purposes.
It's unheard of.
It's never happened before or after.
Yeah.
To me or I don't know if I've seen that to anybody else.
No.
But I literally, I can tell you I maybe got one, like, negative comment.
That's great.
And from all walks of life, you know?
Yeah, yeah.
Like, race, class, gender, like, everybody.
So it was very, it was very intriguing, but then you get more and more famous and that
starts to shift where literally, like, anything you say can be taken as you being confrontational
because that's how people were introduced to you.
Right.
Or the people booking you or creating the whatever, they want you to do that.
And even in the book, like, I just talk about, like, just the realities of, like, having to
know, like, yourself.
Like, I'm a type A personality.
Like, I'm very particular.
I'm very efficient about things.
Like, people can take that.
Like, you know, I'm, as a black woman, like, there's this already I'm walking in with a
stigma for a lot of people of, like, oh, okay, well, let's see what she's going to
be like.
Like, you know, if you are somebody who has a reputation for, quote, unquote, being difficult,
which I have that reputation, you, that's one of those words that's, like, crazy.
Difficult, right.
Where, like, people don't really, like, it's just, it's, it's, it's a scarlet letter word.
Yeah.
But you don't know what it really means.
Right.
Because, like, for some people, it's like, oh, she's not difficult.
Like, she just knows what she wants.
Yeah.
She stands up for herself.
But then for some people, they'd be like, exactly.
Who the fuck wants to deal with that shit?
Right.
Fortune is very difficult.
I am, Tom.
And we know exactly what it means.